AMY **MERRILL**

1235 E Mary lane, Gilbert, AZ 85295 | H: 480-570-2696 | amyjomerrill12@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Diligent Sales/Customer Service Representative offering over 2-year record in customer support and strong aptitude for working with little supervision. Competent in listening to customer needs, meeting quality standards and staying current on product and service updates. Highly empathetic and supportive team player.

SKILLS

- Client management
- Problem-solving abilities
- Internet Sales
- Customer Service
- Organizational Skills

- Sales operations
- Adaptive team player
- Active listening
- Telephone Skills
- Communication Skills

EXPERIENCE

06/2016 to 12/2018

Internet Sales Manager

Henry Brown Automotive — Gilbert, AZ

- Maintained relationships and followed up with customers.
- Negotiated product sales and trade-in deals for maximum profit.
- Set and exceeded sales goals for Dec 2016 through 2018.
- Provided near real-time price quotes for Buick and GMC vehicles.
- Identified lucrative business prospects through cold calling, networking, marketing and database leads.
- Cultivated long-term relationships with clients to accurately quote pricing and terms that achieve customer objectives.
- Improved profitability by developing pipeline utilizing multiple sales penetration strategies.
- Led and motivated 6-person team of sales professionals working with automotive sales.

01/2003 to 11/2005

Loan Officer

Maricopa Mortgage — Phoenix, AZ

- Educated customers on variety of loan products and available credit options to promote valuable decision-making.
- Analyzed applicants' financial status, credit and property evaluation to determine feasibility of granting loan.
- Executed the loan origination process, including ordering credit reports, appraisals and preliminary title reports.
- Delivered prompt, accurate and excellent customer service.
- Built a business base by word of mouth as a result of maintaining positive relationships with former borrowers.
- Served as liaison between borrowers and lenders and collaborated with both parties to obtain optimal loans for home purchases.
- Clarified all details in regards to the mortgage loan process so that the borrower was well-educated.

• Wrote contract documents, purchase agreements and closing statements.

05/2003 to 05/2005

Real Estate Agent

Evolution Realty — Phoenix, AZ

- Successfully guided home buyers and sellers through sales and purchase of properties.
- Followed up with prospects throughout the sales process.
- Coordinated appointments with prospective buyers to showcase houses and plots.
- Showed building models to prospects based on expressed needs and preferences.
- Wrote contract documents, purchase agreements and closing statements.
- Actively follow-up with prospects and hot leads.
- Showed residential properties and explained the features, value and benefits of available homes.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2019 Full Stack Web Development Certificate/in process: Web Development

University of Arizona — Gilbert, AZ

2003 Real Estate

Arizona School of Real Estate — Scottsdale

Associate of Arts: Business

Maricopa Community Colleges - Mesa Community College — Mesa, AZ

VOLUNTEER WORK

Served a full-time 18 month mission for the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints.

Spanish Speaking/Dominican Republic

Dec 2000 to August 2001